<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walking Diary</title>
    <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Walking Diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://richardhsu.net/ray2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Diary: Hobby</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/07/08/corona-diary-hobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/07/08/corona-diary-hobby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing being quarantined at home for so long teaches you is being creative about how you spend your time. I look at my dad’s routine, he basically just sleeps, eats, and watches TV/mobile/iPad, and very little of anything else. And that got me thinking that I need something other than just being a couch potato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am thinking, everyone needs to have some kind of hobby/interest to keep us busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to find one for myself. At various times I tried learning guitar, learning mandarin, doing some creative writing. All eventually either I gave up on or lost interest in. The only interest I have which has sustained me all these years is my love for reading but that again is a little too passive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has to involve some, even minor physical activity. I will keep looking else I will end up like my dad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Diary: Steer into the skid</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/05/21/corona-diary-steer-into-the-skid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/05/21/corona-diary-steer-into-the-skid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was watching a TWiT podcast and one guest, Amy Webb, explained a new concept(to me) which I found very interesting. She called it ‘Steer into the skid’, which I later found is a saying people use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She explained that if there is uncertainty we should not do what the initial normal reaction would be, and just try to stop immediately and try to return to normal. But instead to try to lean into the problem and accept the issue, and adjust accordingly and find a new way to deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like if you are driving and suddenly hit an icy road and start to skid. A normal reaction would be to put the brake and stop immediately. This may make things worse but instead what you should do is, let it skid and try to slowly steer towards the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said this in the context of the Coronavirus issue the whole world is facing currently. She explains that it is a wrong idea to just want to get everything back to normal. Currently a lot of countries have been in severe lockdown mode for a long period, and because of that economy has suffered badly. So a lot of people are getting restless and want the businesses to open up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time we should not just try to go back to normal, business as usual. The better solution is to try and find a new solution( a new way of living), accept that this will go on for a year or more, and find a new way to cope with this. Once we accept the problem then we can start working towards a creative solution even though it would not meet our demand to get back to normal. We all must accept the new normal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing tools</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/05/07/writing-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/05/07/writing-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of tools that helps me write. It is ranging from simple note-taking to writing for my blog. What is common to them is that they are simple to use and are free tools( Since I am a cheap person 🙂) Most of them also work across devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OneNote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to take notes. I take notes for all sorts of things like the TO-DO list, for some information, for planning, organizing. Taking notes helps me in planning, decision making. Also useful for a quick lookup when the information is needed. This is my go-to application for note-taking. It is simple to use and since it syncs to the cloud, I can access my notes everywhere. I use it mostly as an android application on my smartphone. Since it is always with me, It helps me keep useful information available to me all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notepad++&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a Windows guy, I used to use notepad a lot for short note-taking. Now I use this application instead. I use it basically for taking rough notes, so no fancy formatting needed, only just plain texts will do. It does provide me with certain extra features that notepad did not like: multiple tabs for taking different notes. It is also helpful when I need to do a small edit of HTML, code files as it supports multiple languages. I just like this because the application is lightweight and simple to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Docs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to use Office Word a lot earlier, but ever since I discovered this, I use this mostly. Firstly it is free, secondly, for my purpose, this is more than sufficient. It has all the main features that I require, like simple formatting, spelling, and grammar checking. It lets you download the document as Word file or as PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use this extensively for all my writings, like for documentation for any projects, notes, information details for various stuff. Study notes on various topics. My usual flow when writing a blog would be to first write it here, it provides me the basic spelling checks, grammatical checks, and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has also become my repository of all notes, documentations. Since I can access it any place across any device that becomes very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grammarly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great tool to help you write better, it provides you with all the basic spell checking and grammatical checking. Additionally, it provides you helpful tips/suggestions to a written sentence. Though Google docs is pretty good, this application is even better in helping you with better writings. This has become my go-to now, whenever I need to write something important. I would put the text here and just verify what needs to be changed, and in general, I find I need to correct many mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/04/19/data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/04/19/data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today‘s world data is super important, those who have a lot of it become successful, like Google, Facebook, Amazon. The more data you have the better knowledge you have and so decision making becomes easier. For example, when a lot of people buy a product on Amazon, Amazon will get the information firstly to stock more of that product, secondly, since that kind of product is very popular, so introduce more of the same in the Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individually also we must consume as much information(data) as we can. We live in an era where we have an abundance of it. We are constantly bombarded with it from everywhere. The Internet, the smartphone have made it possible for the free flow of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is good we have a lot of data but equally important part is how you interpret it. A person can look at a set of data and interpret it differently than others. What is real, what is fake, how do you decide. Trump has made popular the term ‘fake news’. It has become far too easy to spread fake as real, and real as fake cause most people are not doing enough critical analysis of the data they are being given. They instead just trust the source. So a Trump supporter will believe whatever he says even if it is ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me give an example of data interpretation and why it is important. A few months ago I went to church, and the priest gave a sermon. Generally, like many people, it is hard for me to pay close attention to what the priest is saying, my head goes to someplace else after some time :). Every once in a while you will find a preacher saying something interesting. This was that time, the priest was able to get my attention from the very beginning by the way he talked. He was a very good speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one part of his sermon, he said and I am paraphrasing here, that from one study the growth from the year 2010 to 2015 of ‘common-law marriage’ (a marriage without a civil or ecclesiastical ceremony, generally resulting from an agreement to marry followed by the couple&amp;rsquo;s living together.) has been 80% while normal marriage has been 40%. If you listen to it without thinking much, it looks like people just living together has become much more than who is getting married. Since the person speaking here is a priest, this is very bad news. Also, he is an important person to his listener, most people take it in and believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with that interpretation is this, the comparison is not correct unless you provide more context to it. Since the number of ‘common-law marriages’ against ‘normal marriage’ is very small, it will grow at a much faster rate than ‘normal marriage’. Here is an example with numbers. Say in 2010 the number of ‘common-law marriages’ was 10, and the number of ‘normal marriages’ was 1000. In 2015 the number of ‘common-law marriages’ was 18, that is 8 more people got added to it, which makes it an 80% growth. And similarly, in 2015 the number of ‘normal marriages’ was 1400, that is 400 more people got added to it, which makes it a 40% growth. So if you just look at the growth rate and compare the two, 80% is so much more than 40%, but in fact, in the 5 years ‘common-law marriages’ increased by 8 and ‘normal marriages’ increased by 400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the context here is important, I am not saying the priest is deliberately misleading his congregation. He may have been sincere in his approach, but failed to give more context to those numbers. But this is not always true for most people/organizations, we are constantly being fed some data/news to deliberately mislead us. What is important is to learn to do critical thinking (analysis of the data), don&amp;rsquo;t just accept whatever is being told to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Education</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/03/09/on-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/03/09/on-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I was contemplating doing recently was joining Teach For India. It is a wonderful organization dedicated to improving education in India. They teach children and have a 2 years fellowship where you learn to teach and teach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teachforindia.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.teachforindia.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join one step was to write 3 essays on three different topics. Here is one I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always had a desire to get into educating children. Teaching for me is one noble profession. You are just not educating the children to be better at their studies, you are also giving valuable life lessons for them to grow up to become better human beings. Teachers are role models. I still fondly remember many of my teachers, from whom I have learned so much. They are one big reason why I have been successful in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an excellent education and I believe every child deserves the same. There is extreme poverty all over India and one big reason is education. When children do not have basic education. It is very difficult for them to improve their lives and those of their family when they grow up. Once you do not have an education you also lack ambition sometimes. The reverse is with good education you know you can achieve so much more. Basic education for me is not just when a child can read, write, do the math, learn about science, history, geography, etc, but also when a child can solve problems logically, use their brain creatively. The child has to be able to think out of the box, their thoughts should not be limited to certain textbooks only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My background is in software engineering. I think my experience in software and current technology would benefit students greatly. I would be able to not only teach the course but also give a fresh perspective to the students. Just like in the software industry where you have to constantly be updated to the new technologies. I believe that the education industry has to constantly try to improve ( which Teach For India is already doing). One way is to embrace more technologies and have a better understanding of it to prepare the students for the future world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal during the 2-year fellowship is to learn how to teach better and then to implement it and try to improve the education of children. After the 2 years, I intend to keep educating in some form and find other ways to contribute like using my software knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I did not go through with the application eventually, tabling the idea for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luck</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/01/22/luck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2020/01/22/luck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I would not call myself a lucky person. I have never won any lottery. In Chinese New Year, whenever I had played the card game 21, I had lost most of the time. Any game involving luck, I am just not very good at it. So I avoid it, I do not gamble, even a small amount for fun. Luck does not seem to be on my side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying that in any game which involves luck there is a mathematical probability that you should win at some point, that is if you play long enough. Of course, the gambling rule is the house always wins. If you play long enough, in general, you might win some but you will lose most of the time. The exception is, if you are a really lucky person, then the probability changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my friends religiously plays a lottery game, called ‘Pick 4’. The idea is simple, you buy a ticket which is valid for the day, you pick 4 numbers. Everyday day, 4 numbers are generated in the lottery system. If all numbers match and in that order you win the big price, if not in the order you win lesser but still a decent amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he has been playing every day the same set of numbers for over a year. Logic(probability) would say, that series of numbers will come up at some point. Now we were spending the afternoon together, a phone call comes up and my friend gets a call from another of his friend who knows his habit with the lottery. He says your number has come up, the friend checks the website and yes those numbers have won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of joy, he starts cursing. Guess what he did not buy a lottery ticket today! He has spent a year with it, and the day he does not buy, that number shows up. Luck, sometimes you just don’t have it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educated fool</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/10/25/educated-fool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/10/25/educated-fool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a scooter which needed the pollution to be checked to get the pollution certificate. Since it was not updated for a long time, the person who does the checking told us to go to the Motor Vehicle office to get it fixed as his system said that my scooter details were not updated, so he was not able to check it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, whenever you have to go to the government office to get things done, it is complicated to do, lots of processes, lots of running around different places, time-consuming. So the easy way out is to pay some agents to do the work for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So me and my cousin went to the office, we were told before this work did not cost us any fee. When we arrived at the entrance we were immediately surrounded by a few people who told us that they would do the work for us, we would just need to pay additionally 100Rs for their service. This sounded us to be a good deal( wrong), as we were not familiar with the process to do the task. If these people would do at that cost, it was well worth it. So I provided them with the Scooter Smart card, for them to find out the details of the case and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some time, they came back with a list of issues with my scooter. They said that there were pending cases with the scooter so fine had to be paid, the scooter details were blocked in the system so they have to unblock it, they also had to update the system with the scooter details. Everything would cost us 6000+, we suspected they were making things up, as if there were cases against the scooter, we would have received a message for it. We argued for some time, then told them to just do the minimum necessary so we could get the pollution check done. They said it would need an update in the system, and it would cost 2000Rs, they would provide a receipt for it. So I thought this was reasonable( wrong again) and gave them the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some more time, they came back and told me I had to go to one office, and provide the xerox of the smart card, and provide other information to the officer. One reason you pay these people is so that you do not have to stand in line for hours to eventually get the thing done. They should have internal contacts and thereby get it done without any hassle. I was told to stand in line, saying only 10 people in front of me, and it would be very quick. At this point, I had a feeling that these people were fooling me, as they did not seem to have done much. Anyway, I stood in line, found out there were more than 30 people in front. All of them came for the same reason but I was guessing they did not go through these people. I had to wait in line for 1 hour plus, already frustrated, then when I reach the end, the officer looked at my papers and said I had to get an additional certificate from the scooter maker(Honda), then come back again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This got me upset as I wasted all my time in the queue, I would have to get back in it again. One reason you pay agent is, they would know the full process, know all papers required, so you would not need to run around to find out if you did it by yourself. I found these guys and again argued that they wasted my time and I would have to get back in the queue, and since the closing time was arriving the thing would not be done. They told me when I get back they would put me right in front of the queue so I did not have to wait( guess what wrong again).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to Honda and got the certificate and came back, these people took me in line and told me to go in front, I went in front but already knew none of the people who were in the line already for hours, would entertain the thought of me getting in front. The agent had already by now left. I did not argue much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to the end of the line and waited for another one hour plus, hoping the office would not close and I would then need to come back another day to this all over again. Thankfully, the officer extended the office time, and I eventually got things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later I found out from my cousin, as he talked to a few people who had done the same thing that there was no requirement of money. Of Course, by now I could not track any of the agents, they had all left for the day. I had been fooled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cousin commented “Bhai, what happened to your education”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The difficult thing about teaching is learning</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/08/21/the-difficult-thing-about-teaching-is-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/08/21/the-difficult-thing-about-teaching-is-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always fancied myself as a teacher, and do like the concept of teaching. I consider it still one of the few noble professions, where people in general still respect. The idea of imparting knowledge, wisdom to another person especially to kids is powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have over the years taught a few kids as tuitions, with mixed results. Some did well, some did not. Other than those small experience I have had not much. The idea though always interested me. So an opportunity came where an NGO called &lt;a href=&#34;http://theblueturtlecentre.com/WordPress3/&#34;&gt;Blue Turtle&lt;/a&gt;, needed a computer teacher and I agreed to do it. I started teaching computers on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue I face is the interest from the children to learn, many times you see in their eyes/ body language that they are just not interested in learning or learning that topic which is being taught. It becomes difficult to teach if your student does not want to learn. You lose your motivation to teach them also after some time. The challenge is trying to make learning interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many times the topics are difficult to understand for a kid. So they tend to give up, and unless forced will not want to learn them. Here you try to simplify the complex topics so it becomes easier to digest for them. Once they start getting it, the interest comes more naturally. As a teacher, the way you teach is also a learning experience in itself, something works for some students and sometimes it does not for others. If I am to succeed I have to learn quickly as to how to teach. The good student is easy to teach to get better. The real challenge comes with the weaker students, can I bring them up a few levels. Can I make them want to learn? That is the question I will probably try to find an answer in the next few months or even years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pokemon GO</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/07/26/pokemon-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/07/26/pokemon-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest addiction is this game. I remember it became a huge rage some 3 years back when it was first launched. One of the reasons it became popular was because a lot of people were going to great lengths just to just catch some Pokemon! Like people would often trespass to some private property. Hugh number of people would travel long distances. There are several funny videos on the net to see this kind of craziness for a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is simple, and anyone can start playing without knowing much. You just have to travel distances and catch digital creatures called Pokemon, with throwing a ball(Pokeball) at it. Once you exhaust the Pokeballs you have, you can get more by visiting PokeStops. These PokeStops are situated in different parts of the city. For example, a metro station might have a Pokestop. The game is location-based, played in the virtual world of an actual street map. So imagine Google map, you can see the roads and if you walk, you can see your progress in the virtual map. Just add Pokemons, PokeStops to it, and that is the game. You walk to collect Pokeball, you walk, you find Pokemon then try to catch it. Simple and a lot of fun. Of Course, there is more complexity to the game, once you are more familiar with it, you will learn more about making friends, sharing gifts, fighting battles with other Pokemon, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am no good with video games, it&amp;rsquo;s something to do with patience and/or my lack of eye finger coordination. Last time I played a virtual game at length was Age of Empires which was more than a decade ago. This game is perfect for me, I play at a leisurely pace. No super skill is required, just willingness to travel which I do a lot anyway. It still does not fully explain why I am becoming addicted to it. Maybe the simple task-reward nature of the game suits my taste. Maybe the pseudo-social nature of it, you do make friends in the game and help each other but everyone uses alias and real identity is never known. It could also be the adventure aspect of it where you keep looking and suddenly find a new Pokemon. Bottomline for a person who does not play any virtual game I play this game a lot. Which is starting to worry me :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a downside to this game, since it is location-based, it needs you to always provide your location. If you are a privacy focus then this might be a no-no for you. For me the fun I have with it, I am OK with that trade. (hoping in future I don&amp;rsquo;t find news that it has been used inappropriately :) ). I like it so much that I recently spent 29 Rs to buy 100 PokeCoins!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chernobyl</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/06/20/chernobyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/06/20/chernobyl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is the cost of lies? It’s not that we will mistake them for the truth. The real danger is that, if we hear enough lies, then we no longer recognize the truth at all. What can we do then? What else is left but to abandon even the hope of truth and content ourselves instead with stories? In these stories, it doesn’t matter who the heroes are. All we want to know is who is to blame.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just finished watching the mini-series, it&amp;rsquo;s a must watch, high-quality stuff. I must say HBO is making some very good shows. What I like about the show is the drama created is very intense, you are instantly intrigued from the start, and the pace keeps up right till the end. The production quality and acting are superb. The other thing I like about it is, it is thought-provoking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have all heard read about the Chernobyl disaster, but for most people, like me, we do not realize the magnitude of the disaster, the high cost and the danger which was avoided. This brings the Chernobyl disaster into better perspective for me. I read about it a bit, even though it has some fiction in it. I will say it is an important work, which hopefully more people see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is especially important now, cause if you look at the world now, it is full of lies/fake news/propaganda. It caused the Chernobyl disaster to happen then, and we are going to have another disaster if we do not do something about it. If we just let lies win, it will happen. For example, take something like climate change. It is a fact, it is a disaster waiting to happen if we do not do enough. But here also lots of lies are spread, and if powerful people like Trump who has large followers keep at the lies, keep disbelieving, then we are going to build this up and over time another disaster will happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Every lie we tell incurs a debt to the truth. Sooner or later that debt is paid.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I listen to</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/03/21/what-i-listen-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2019/03/21/what-i-listen-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The good thing about a long commute between home and work is that you have lots of free time which you can utilize to good use. One way I utilize that time is to listen to music and podcast. I love listening to these, here is a list of current favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaana is great if you love music and spend lots of time listening to it. It is cross-platform, so I can access it on the web and as an app on my phone. I use to use the free version which was great, but now I pay for the subscription which cost me 200 Rs for 6 months. It is a great deal for me as its cheap, there are no ads, also the feature to download music and listen offline is very useful, as there are many places like metro where the net is weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gaana.com/&#34;&gt;https://gaana.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Week in Tech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Twit, I listen to many of their shows regularly. My favorite among them is This week in tech. The show is produced very well, Leo is a great host, and generally, they bring a lot of very good guest. The conversation is often insightful, interesting and fun. They also dig deep into topics I have interest in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twit.tv/shows/this-week-in-tech&#34;&gt;https://twit.tv/shows/this-week-in-tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Week in Google&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second show I regularly listen to on Twit. It is very similar to TwiT, only it is more focused on Google and has fixed guests. Jeff Jarvis and Stacey Higginbotham both are great and gives interesting perspective in the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twit.tv/shows/this-week-in-google&#34;&gt;https://twit.tv/shows/this-week-in-google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Filmcast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching films is one of my favorite pastimes. I also like reading, listening to it. I found this podcast after listening to a few others, and I like this one more because of how the three guys talk about it. They talk about the latest movies and reviews them, the conversation is interesting and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-filmcast&#34;&gt;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-filmcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rewatchables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to Filmcast podcast this one also has great hosts who talk in depth about a movie. Its USP is it selects movie based on how rewatchable it is. We all have our old favorite movies which we rewatch multiple times. This is great as basically, they are talking about those special movies. I discovered many good old movies which I have not to watch before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-ringer/the-rewatchables&#34;&gt;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-ringer/the-rewatchables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seinfeld</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/12/27/seinfeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/12/27/seinfeld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love viewing TV/Movies and have many favorites, which I keep rewatching and loving it. Though If you told me to pick one if I ever were to be stuck in an island, and had only one choice, I would take the seasons of Seinfeld. Even now whenever any episode shows on TV, I would watch and enjoy it. The jokes never get old for me, even when I know all of them, all the punchlines, it still makes me laugh. Recently with Amazon prime video subscription, I was able to go through all the seasons of Seinfeld and thoroughly enjoyed all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seinfeld is one of those rare gems of a show which is perfect in everywhere. It is insanely funny, and the jokes are even funny after so many years. The show’s tagline is “Show about nothing” but the great thing about Seinfeld is it talked about everything and joked about everything. The characters are all very memorable and brilliantly played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this might be different for the younger generation. I watched a Youtube video of teenagers, who were shown clips of Seinfeld and was asked about their reactions. Many still found it funny but there were some who says that the jokes not politically correct. These days you have to be careful what you say which is a shame. There are too many judgments made on every single thing. In my opinion, comedy should have the freedom to do what it like, if you do not like a particular routine or a particular comic, you can just ignore it. There is no need to be angry and call for the ban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some references in life, and Seinfeld is one of them, once in a while I would remember a particular quote of it, a particular scenario of how it played out and apply it. There are many quotable quotes, here are some samples I like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you can’t say something bad about a relationship you shouldn’t say anything at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Jerry, just remember, it&amp;rsquo;s not a lie if you believe it.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When you look annoyed all the time, people think that you&amp;rsquo;re busy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We&amp;rsquo;re Not Gay. Not That There&amp;rsquo;s Anything Wrong with That.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to be the one person who doesn&amp;rsquo;t die with dignity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Festivus for the rest of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/11/06/cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/11/06/cooking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“the practice or skill of preparing food by combining, mixing, and heating ingredients.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my whole life I have been eating food without worrying/wondering much about the cooking part. I know the basics of what goes on there. I even have tried on rare occasions few dishes, with varied success. With few of my family members have made their livelihood doing just that so the knowledge and appreciation are there, but recently I have got a better understanding and appreciation for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All my life, I had the fortune of being around people who can cook, so good food was never an issue. Last month I had to go to Norway for work for 3 weeks. Since I do not know how to cook, I was prepared to eat outside mostly and occasionally cook Maggi and other ready-made variety food. Accepting the fact that it would probably not be an enjoyable experience or going to be an expensive one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reaching there I had the good fortune of meeting a group of friends from south India who stayed in the same hotel and who actually could prepare a decent meal! Since we all went for work, our schedule was mostly to spend the day in office, come back in the evening, rest a bit then cooking started, dinner, a little rest, then sleep and so on the next day. In this, the time we spent was during the cooking process took from 1 to 2 hours to cook, sometimes more. Since we all were in the same room, and the room itself was small, we all took part in the cooking process. Apart from cutting some vegetables, I did very little else other than watch with interest how the process was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starter, I realized that even cooking seemingly simple dishes took quite a long time to do. The cook had to be constantly very attentive and patient as there are several periods involving doing lots of things, then a long period of wait. I am a science student and most things I do well, it is because I have a system and process to do it. Like making tea, I know how many people to drink so I calculate the cups of water/milk, teaspoons of sugar/tea. I am always amazed by how home cooking is many times not done by proper measurements but by natural instinct as to how much ingredients to add. My mum regularly says while cooking she puts things anadaj se(by guess), and similarly, the person who cooks here did the same. He used to put some ingredients, somehow he knew and the food tasted great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not sure I ever will learn to cook much but it is an art I do appreciate more now after spending so many hours around it. I did also come around an article recently talking about if you can&amp;rsquo;t cook it is nothing to be proud of, and I agree everyone should make at least some effort to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hindustantimes.com/brunch/can-t-cook-or-won-t-cook/story-n3fznopKBssGVD8A7gjViL.html&#34;&gt;https://www.hindustantimes.com/brunch/can-t-cook-or-won-t-cook/story-n3fznopKBssGVD8A7gjViL.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When did doctor stop caring</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/07/01/when-did-doctor-stop-caring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/07/01/when-did-doctor-stop-caring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I took my dad to see his regular diabetes doctor. He has been visiting the same doctor for a while now, and generally goes on his own. This time I thought it would be good if I talked to the doctor myself, as whenever I asked dad after a visit he says the doctor did not say anything just that everything is normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I took off from work and reached the clinic at 4 PM. The doctor came at 5:30 PM that already frustrated me, but I would have given the doctor a pass on being late as it may be he was checking on other patients. My dad says this happens everytime he goes, so this doctor is a regular latecomer and just does not value his patients time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, when we go inside his chamber he is talking on his phone, signals us to sit. The attitude already seems off to me. He checks the reports and just writes in the prescription to continue same medication and to visit him again in three months. I try to ask questions and he gives a very little answer, I almost have to more forceful with my questions for him to give a better answer. But that also was not why I got upset. What upset me was even before we left and my dad was having some parting words with him, he was already looking at his phone barely acknowledging us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been noticing this kind of behaviour by few doctors. To me, doctors like teachers are only a few noble profession. You do it not only because you make money but also because you really care and you want to help people. Maybe I am being foolish here in thinking I should expect it to be better. I do know quite a few doctors who do show kindness, but its increasing rare which is a shame.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for vacation</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/06/01/time-for-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/06/01/time-for-vacation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day I was listening to the radio, and the discussion going on between the people were if they used up their leaves which they are entitled to by their respective companies. Two out of three said they did not take many leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every new month I get a mail from HR giving the status of leaves I have taken and what is pending. Last checked I have accumulated 136 outstanding leaves! What is more astounding is, it is not as if I can cash these pending leaves. One day when policy change it will just be reset. So I might have nothing to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think that if I did not need it why to take leaves. I generally am healthy and on only few occasions I would take a long vacation. So over nine years, I have piled up this number. Which I now feel is a wastage, I should take more leaves even if it means sitting at home and watching the full Breaking Bad series in one go 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merci Arsene</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/05/01/merci-arsene/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/05/01/merci-arsene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love sports, especially football. Arsenal is the only club I can say am a true fan of. It all started in the late 90s, in those days not like now when you have a lot of live sport on TV but World cup football was a still big deal, everyone would tune in and watch it. In one the matches, I remember one particular goal by Bergkamp &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xtXo-8tThAg&#34;&gt;goal&lt;/a&gt;  in the world cup that fascinated me. It was just sublime skill, from there on I became a fan of Bergkamp, of course, he went on to score many more beautiful &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zw8RaB_ioRs&#34;&gt;goals&lt;/a&gt;. Since I was a fan and he came to Arsenal I started following Arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great time to follow the gunners, they use to regularly win trophies or at least be challenging for the top prize. Then there was the unbelievable invincible team. Most of all I love Arsenal because of how they played. They played the beautiful game beautifully. The main reason was that they had a manager in Arsene Wenger, whose philosophy was simple. He believed that football has to be played in a certain way, and that way was beautiful passing attacking football. Under him, Arsenal became from being called ‘Boring, boring’ to one most of the most entertaining club. You just have to see some of the team goals they have scored to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q7wNwkJ4CB4&#34;&gt;see that&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was responsible for bringing numerous exciting footballers we got to see, Bergkamp, Pires, Henry, Fabregas, Ozil and so on. He had enormous faith in his brand of football. His belief in that philosophy was so strong that, the second decade of his career though there was plenty of criticism he never wavered. Many argue, including me that he was too set in his way. Arsenal needed a change and in his last few years, most people could see that we were not really challenging for the major trophies, worse we were probably degrading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the club even when it did not want to, had to let him go. I am happy it went this way, and unlike other clubs which fires managers so easily. Arsenal showed patience and did it the dignified way. There are many qualities I admire about him when you hear him speak there is always a dignity to it. He is a man of top quality, his conduct has always been top class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He might not have won as many trophies as I would have liked. But I would not trade watching wonderful football for it. Thank you, Arsene for all the entertainment. Merci Arsene.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandarmani</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/04/01/mandarmani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/04/01/mandarmani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite short vacation destination is a place called Mandarmani. It is a seaside resort village. To travel to it, you can take a bus/car ride from Calcutta which will take you 4 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like it because the beach is nice and there are generally not many people. It is very different to the more famous Digha beach, there are just too many people around there. The hotels are all close to the beach itself, so you will get a great view and good breeze. The food served is very tasty if you like Bengali cuisine. One downside though is for what the hotel provides its a bit expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing for sightseeing, it’s just beach, you can see some crabs but that’s it. If you just want to chill it’s an ideal place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://500px.com/hsushenon/galleries/mandarmani&#34;&gt;https://500px.com/hsushenon/galleries/mandarmani&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who do i read</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/03/30/who-do-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/03/30/who-do-i-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://virsanghvi.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vir Sanghvi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is probably the oldest writer I still follow now regularly. I started to read him when an article came in Hindustan Times on Sunday. He writes on varied topics mostly related to India. He is also a very good food critic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thurrott.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Thurrott&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was mentioned to me by my brother, from then on I have been following his posts. I have a keen interest in all thing Microsoft, and he writes very well about them. I also like the fact that he is very critical in his writings, you can’t call him a fanboy. If you read many tech writers, sometimes it feels like there is a bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://om.co/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Om Malik&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my regular podcast watches is twit, he comes sometimes and I found his thoughts interesting.  His blog is mostly tech and related stuff, he writes very well, worth a read.Additionally, his photography skill is pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bijansabet.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bijan Sabet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Om’s post mentioned him, he is an amazing photographer. I love his work, especially the very interesting one he did on taking one photo per day for a whole year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://seemagoswami.blogspot.in/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seema Goswami&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started reading her short article in the Sunday magazine which came with Hindustan Times newspaper. Her sharp and witty take on different topics make her article very interesting to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look up</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/03/01/look-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/03/01/look-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of late I have noticed that whenever I am traveling I spent a lot of time staring at my mobile. This is probably true for most people these days who have a smartphone. Whenever a moment arrives that you are not doing anything, your automatic tendency is to fetch your phone and start going through the messages, social sites, games etc. One of the things I enjoy to do is travel, even for short trip as I like to see new things. When you look out of the window of the vehicle even for the same journey there is always something new and interesting happening. So when I started to stick to my phone longer and longer, it was a cause of some alarm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day when a lift arrived at the ground floor we saw a guy still busy with his phone and did not step out till someone told him to. Obviously later the people around started complaining how the newer generation are completely addicted to their phone these days. We all have noticed that even in a social gathering where people are expected to interact, you will see some just look down and play with their phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree more and more it seems like this has become an addiction for a lot of people. They just can’t live without their phone even for a short period. There is a term coined for this FOMO (Fear of missing out) “a pervasive apprehension that others might be having rewarding experiences from which one is absent”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have put a rule on myself, where I make sure I do not spend too much time on the phone. I call it 50%, so basically if I am on a bus and if it takes 40 minutes to arrive at the destination, I will try and not spend more than 20 minutes on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My problem with Aadhaar</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/01/01/my-problem-with-aadhaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2018/01/01/my-problem-with-aadhaar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Aadhaar is the world’s largest biometric ID system, with over 1.19 billion enrolled members as of 30 Nov 2017, representing over 99% of Indians aged 18 and above. World Bank Chief Economist Paul Romer described Aadhaar as ‘the most sophisticated ID programme in the world’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start by saying I totally like the idea of Aadhaar. The idea that almost everyone in India would have an ID that would work as proof of identity in the most scenario and it would be impossible to fake. For a country like India with its complexity and population, to get this done properly has huge benefits. Not only for the individual but also for the government and corporations. The whole identification process would become seamless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My concern is right now it has become more than what it was plan for. Aadhaar is not just an ID card now, it is becoming a monster with all data linked to it. The government has done a fabulous job in getting most Indian to make one. Now it is forcing everyone to link it to all his other data like bank account/phone/tax etc. In itself if you think about it, it is fine if government wants to have everything under one umbrella, the concern is data breach. Once Aadhaar becomes all powerful then if there is a data breach that would be a huge disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I read an article where Bill Gates talks about &lt;a href=&#34;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/my-biggest-disappointment-with-india-is-the-state-of-its-education-bill-gates/articleshow/61679641.cms&#34;&gt;Aadhaar&lt;/a&gt; a bit, very interesting what he says. Here are some quotes “Aadhaar is just a 12-digit lie detector. You may claim to be someone and Aadhaar can tell if you’re speaking the truth or lying. Yes, there are many applications linked to Aadhaar and there are records related to them. Privacy issues can come up with the applications that get built on top of Aadhaar. But none of the records reside on the Aadhaar system itself. The irony is that I often tell Nandan (Nilekani) that if I had built Aadhaar, I would have created it with many more inbuilt capabilities, but Nandan was very careful about not intruding on privacy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the chief architect of Aadhaar Nandan Nilekani, who I respect because of what he has done with Infosys, had the idea from the very beginning of what it should be, at the core a lie detector. Problem is he is no longer in charge, the people now may be modifying the code as we speak and including all sorts of data in it. Another big issue is transparency, information flow has always been a big problem in India, many people say many different things and common people just do not understand fully. Most of the time they just do as told. So there is less clarity on the scope of Aadhaar and many doubts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently multiple cases being fought in the courts right now regarding this. Fundamental to them is the right to privacy, people are arguing that the government cannot force them to link their other data to it. They fear that their data are going to be misused. We will see what the court says, but people’s opinion is split now about Aadhaar. Many people legitimately fear(including me) and there are equally many sound people who argue that these are fears are baseless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have already been few data breaches mainly due to mischievous people who had access to the data and who leak them. The fear is there will be lot more and at larger scale, these are not good signs especially when the people in charge refuse to acknowledge that there are some problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a personal issue with it which raises my doubt. My dad had linked the gas subsidy to his bank in Canara bank long time back, he was getting the subsidy in that bank every time no issue. Then we open an ICICI account for him and connected the Aadhaar to it also(as is needed). The subsidy money started going to ICICI instead of Canara! This happened without our permission! and if I had not checked I would never have known as there was no notification. This kind of things creates doubt about how the system was developed and how its getting implemented now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, Aadhaar is a great concept but currently, it feels like something is broken with it. It is too important to not be near perfect. The government has to get this right. I hope they take security issue seriously and fix the loopholes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two is better than one</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/12/01/two-is-better-than-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/12/01/two-is-better-than-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are few things I have learned along the way which are worth sharing. Here are few which are club together with a general theme being multiple options are always better than having only one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bank account&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a financial article I read sometimes back, basically, it suggested to create accounts for a specific purpose and use it for that purpose only. The idea being that money saved for a particular purpose is not mixed with others, this way it easier to focus and you do not end up over spending. It gave an example of a holiday trip abroad, for some people this might mean a saving for few years. I would not create too many accounts but I like the idea. In general, a person should have at least two.  I have an account for saving and an account for spending. I would put a particular amount from the saving one at some time to the other when it crosses a limit but this way I have more control over my expenditure. Let me explain it like this I have one big bucket of water and one small bucket of water, if I have to take water I almost always take it from the smaller bucket. Knowing it is a smaller bucket you will generally tend to take lesser water. Once you have set your virtual limit, you will be more aware when you spend. Additionally, when you calculate at the year end how it went, the financial statement is easier to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Browser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to buy stuff online, like on Amazon, Flipkart, Snapdeal. You will notice that whenever you visit other sites like Facebook etc, there is a small section which reminds you of that stuff or similar stuff. This is because whenever you go to Amazon etc and look for a stuff to buy, it ‘remembers’ it in the browser, then feeds it as an ad when you visit other sites. At least for me, this is very annoying. One simple hack I found of dealing with it is, if I need to buy things I use another browser to do it, not my regular one. Like I regularly use Firefox, it’s my default but If I need to buy anything online, I will use IE or Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current email clients are pretty good at segregating emails to a category and prioritizing important emails. But this does not work perfectly, and If you are someone who gets a lot of emails, you will soon have a mess. What I do is create separate accounts for the separate purpose. So I have one mail id I use only for my family and close friend. Another for banks and other such related stuff. Yet another for public purposes. I have even one which is basically for junk, sometimes you require to give the email to try stuff. That is probably one too many but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonetization</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/11/01/demonetization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/11/01/demonetization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year this time, the Prime minister announced demonetization with immediate effect. At that time I thought that the drastic step was a game changer. It all depended on how well the government was going to implement it. It soon became clear they had not done their homework, they had not done proper planning to take such a huge step which upset such a large part of the economy. They obviously did not fully understand the enormity of the task, did not understand the obvious problems which will come out. To be fair this kind of step, one cannot be fully prepared and some surprises were expected, but continuous missteps which caused innumerable pains for the common man were inexcusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cash drought dragged on from days to weeks, only after a couple of months things started to get back to normal. In the meantime, many businesses slow down, some even shut down.The ripple effect was huge, workers were not paid or started to find that they were out of a job. Farmers had no cash to put into their crops and had to sell existing crops at a much more lower rate, marriages were postponed or severely scaled down. Numerous deaths were accounted for which directly/indirectly related to demonetization. Most people were not willing to spend, so economy came to a grinding halt. At that point, I was increasingly getting frustrated at the state of affair but I also noted that it was not the right time to judge if this exercise was worth it. We needed to wait for probably 6 more months before we see the full effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year now, my opinion is that by most accounts economy has been hit badly, it has still not recovered yet, not sure it will anytime soon. Growth had slowed down. The push to get people to be less dependent on cash and more on the digital transactions worked initially but once people had cash again, most still prefer cash. There is still a long way before we become a mostly cashless society(note less cash means less likelihood of black money). The initial opinion was that a good portion of the black money which people stored in the banned 500 and 1000 notes would not be allowed back in the system as these were ill-gotten/unaccounted money so those people would be reluctant to expose themselves, so a loss for black money hoarders. Recently RBI has said more than 98% of the demonetized cash had come back to the system that means people were able to dupe the system and convert their black money. There is a famous word in Hindi, which is one of my favorite called ‘jugaad’, the government underestimated the people, they always find some way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though my opinion is mostly negative, there were some positives, more people have started to use banks and other digital options. There was a surge in tax filings, the government was able to collect a lot. (The more the people get into the tax system the better it is for the whole country.) I have to give it to the government also, though there were many negatives, in many ways this was a loss for the economy but they were able to score high politically. They won the perception battle. People like me are in the minority, most people still view this exercise as a positive. For any politician that is what eventually matters most, if people agree with your policy then they will vote for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sundarban</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/10/01/sundarban/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/10/01/sundarban/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Sundarbans is a vast forest in the coastal region of the Bay of Bengal, considered one of the natural wonders of the world, it was recognized in 1997 as a UNESCO World Heritage Site”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This puja me and my brother went on a trip to Sundarban. We took a package tour from a tour agency called Jupiter travels. It costs 4500Rs per person, which is quite reasonable. You can choose the more expensive package which would mean better boat/hotel/food, for us this was just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus picked us from Science City and dropped us to Godhkhali, from there it was another 2 hours of a leisurely motorboat ride to our resort. One of the main fun of the tour is the travel around on the boat enjoying the picturesque natural beauty of Sundarban. If you have sea sickness you can be sure to avoid the trip, because the whole trip will be about traveling in the boat. There are no cars, no roads, there are just multiple small islands of forests and the only way to travel is by the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great attraction of Sundarban is to see the tiger, the tiger here is so famous that they have a special name for it, they are called “Royal Bengal Tiger”, some of these tigers have even earned the reputation of being “man-eater”. Unfortunately, in India, some people have to risks their life to earn a living. So people here goes in the jungle(illegally) to get honey, catch fish etc few of them are attacked and killed sometimes by the Tigers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you travel to Sundarban in hope of seeing these increasingly rare animals, you will most likely be disappointed. Sighting tiger is incredibly difficult, first, the forest is huge and dense and you will have access to only very small portion. Then the tiger population is around 100, so your chance to see one in action is minuscule. Of course, the guide here will play it up and try to keep you excited at the prospect of seeing one :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other interesting point of interests are alligators, dolphins, deer, many different migratory birds. We were able to sight some birds and a deer in the wild, which caused considerable excitement in the boat :). The chances of more sightings depend on the time you go. There was also a cultural programme of folk dance at the resort by local artists. Which was enjoyable to watch, the style of dance and song was very local which becomes very different what we usually see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, if you enjoy nature then Sundarban is great to place to go, even if you do not see the animals you will enjoy the sight of the dense forests, the ride in the boat, the freshness of the natural environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://500px.com/hsushenon/galleries/sundarban&#34;&gt;https://500px.com/hsushenon/galleries/sundarban&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bucket list</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/09/01/bucket-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/09/01/bucket-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bucket list- “a number of experiences or achievements that a person hopes to have or accomplish during their lifetime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my current list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch Arsenal play live at the Emirates Stadium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit Africa (wanna see the Safari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Mandarin (already had two go at it without success)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to play an instrument (had one go at Guitar without success)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Own a home near river/hill (it’s a toss up between the two )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have my own farm (what to grow is yet to be decided)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to be cont…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoT</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/08/01/got/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/08/01/got/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my opinion Games of Thrones is the best TV drama series ever. The seventh season just started with a bang just as it left last season. While watching the first episode starting scene, I got puzzled at what was happening, and I am a person who has watched all the episodes before. I thought I might have been watching something of last season, I recheck and it was season 7, then maybe this is a recap cause the guy died last season how come he is there in the scene!! Of Course, in few moments, it is explained with more killings. GoT captivates you just like this every time, you get instantly hooked even after watching just for few moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is great, a lot of credit goes to George R. R. Martin for writing such a great series of books. Which has so many interesting characters and plots. Many people including me had never heard of the book till the TV series started, the adaptation of the novels to the TV has been perfect. A huge credit to David Benioff and D. B. Weiss for creating the epic drama series. You cannot point to one particular thing as to why the drama is so good. The casts, locations, directions, videography, music are all great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its one of the show that everyone is talking about it, even those who have not watch it has heard about it. It’s everywhere, many newspapers, websites have dedicated sections to just analysis the show. One of the things to watch out for are the spoilers and there are plenty. If you have not watched the last episode then you got to stay away from anything which talks about GoT, even your friends and family cause inadvertently they will give away a plot that would have been interesting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to follow the show. There are many fan sites, Youtube channels dedicated to it and fans really go crazy there. They discuss every scene, every plot to the minute detail. I generally stay away from them because they give out too much detail. I like to watch the show and enjoying what unfolds there. One place I like to read about it is in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/game-of-thrones&#34;&gt;theVerge&lt;/a&gt;. They have series of articles about it, and generally writing is very interesting( Its great place to get tech news also). Every year they conduct an online game in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fantasizr.com/sport/fantasy-game-of-thrones-season-7&#34;&gt;Fantasizr&lt;/a&gt; and I like to participate in it. Rules are simple you choose your team from the show in the start of the season. After every episode, a writer writes an article about it in theVerge, and gives out points depending on the happenings in the episode. Like if you have Arya Stark in your team and she kills someone, you get points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been many memorable moments in the show for me which is one reason I consider it the best. One scene stands out for me, the “Red wedding” episode, it totally shocked me. I have watched many TV shows/movie which has lots of violence in it but this one was so chillingly done that it’s one of the few times I got shocked while watching TV/movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, there is only one more season left, up till now the TV drama was closely following the books but now we are in new territory which makes it more exciting as to what is going to happen. One thing is for sure the show has been able to constantly shock us and so I think the ending might not be what we suppose it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trump</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/07/01/trump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/07/01/trump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schadenfreude&lt;/strong&gt;: It is pleasure derived from the misfortune of others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a lot of people in the world, I too have been obsessing about Trump since he started running for president. I thought after his lost I would forget about him but to my and world’s horror a big portion of Americans voted for him and he became the President of United States!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say I absolutely loathe the guy. He is an example of a bully, racist, sexist, narcissist, and more. A look at him and his behavior and you know the guy is not genuine. It is beyond me how a section(not small) of public continue supporting him even now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I describe my current obsession with Trump as like watching gladiators. You know it&amp;rsquo;s bad, but you just can&amp;rsquo;t take your eyes off it. It&amp;rsquo;s so entertaining, it’s almost like he is on a stage and the world is the audience. He has become one of my favorite topics to read, and every day there seems something interesting is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of a good way is to follow him is to watch Morning Joe on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLDIVi-vBsOEy6jMSt_r_SMj9F5tuqdtKe&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. Here the hosts gives a very good analysis of the political scene of US, plus there are often very good guests who talk sense. As I write this, Trump has used Twitter to insult the hosts of the show with shameful language. It&amp;rsquo;s very unbecoming of the president to talk this way, but by now we all do not expect much better from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As difficult as it is to understand why people would support him there is some good reason why he has become very popular. He is very unconventional, he will say and do things which normally nobody will say/do, this agrees with a lot of people who feel the conventional/established ways have hurt them. He is very good at tapping into the fears of the people. So he will go after Muslims, immigrants, Mexicans etc. He has mastered the art of using Twitter, in some ways, it&amp;rsquo;s because of Twitter he was able to win. He has currently a very strong base who will support him no matter what he says or does. It’s incredible how much he has got away with so far. Every time a controversy happens and you think he will not recover but he seems to bounce back. What will be interesting is to find what is the one thing that eventually brings him down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do hope sooner rather than later he does go. Since to hope for him to change his way is foolish, the guy is never changing. He is currently single-handedly destroying many values of America before long he will start to have the real effect on the world itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book sharing</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/06/01/book-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/06/01/book-sharing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love reading, it&amp;rsquo;s one of few things that can keep me engaged for a long period. Since buying originals is expensive I usually buy second-hand books. I used to go to New market where there is a store which works like a mini library. I go there and pay 20-30 Rs for a novel, usually John Grisham, Jeffrey Archer, Sidney Sheldon, Lee Child. I finish it, return it back and take a new one. Now that bookstore has stopped that scheme so I go to College street and buy a second hand for 70-100 Rs which is still pretty cheap. Since I love reading I like it when other people have the same habit, so sharing book for me is a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a post recently in my Facebook feed which was interesting and a concept which could potentially be great for book lovers. Here is the exact post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am looking for people to participate in a large-scale book exchange. You can be anywhere in the world! All you have to do is buy your favorite book or give one you already had (just one) and send it to a stranger (I&amp;rsquo;ll send their details through private message). You will potentially receive around 36 books back (for your personal collection) to keep - they&amp;rsquo;ll be favorite books from strangers around the world, which is pretty exciting. If you are interested in taking part, please comment below and I will send you all the details! Please don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;lsquo;like&amp;rsquo; &amp;hellip; you need to tell me clearly in comments that you are IN. Happy reading! ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you reply to this post saying you are interested, then the person sharing it sends a private message to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thanks for taking part in the project. So the rules of the book exchange are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#1. Please copy &amp;amp; paste my Facebook status about the project on your timeline (to find the next participants)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#2. You only need to send a book you like/love to this person:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Address of a friend from which he/she got the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write your name, your address and a message on the inside of the book, so people know who and where their book is from.The book doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be a collector’s item, just whatever book you enjoy and in English!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#3. Finally, send this message to the people who commented on your status, and give them my address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Address of your friend from which you got the idea. So that they can send a book to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#4. Then those who comment on your friend&amp;rsquo;s status will send you books, and that&amp;rsquo;s all how it works! When you send the message to those who comment on your status remember to put my address in #2 &amp;amp; put in your address in #3. Happy reading! P.S. Please let me know when you send your book!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide not to participate, please let me know so I can find a replacement. Since everybody made a little financial effort, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair to disrupt the chain. I think giving a book to a stranger is a really exciting idea and you will receive several books in return of just one! I hope you enjoy! Look forward to hearing from you!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea works well if there are more people who are interested, so it spreads. Only one flaw in it is that you are sharing address with a stranger, but if this was not the case then this would not work. Of course, this works on trust system, like I would trust my friend to send my details only to those who they trust. I did send a book to a friend of a friend. So it does work but it will depend on the response you get. I do like the idea though it is limiting as with anything popular in social media eventually it dies down. It would be great to find a better way so that people keep sharing books.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 days without Youtube</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/05/01/2017-05-01-30-days-without-youtube/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/05/01/2017-05-01-30-days-without-youtube/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month was Lent, during that period many Christian do sacrifice of some sort. Most common around me is not eating meat for a day of the week. For my family that is on Friday. I would have done the same usually, if not for an idea my brother put in my head. His family has a tradition where they sit together and everyone picks something to give up during Lent. For my brother, the kids picked a clever one, since they know how much my brother loves Youtube. So my brother was not going to watch Youtube for the whole period of Lent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought that was a great idea even for me. Of late I find myself addicted to Youtube, like most people it is very easy to get sucked into Youtube’s endless loop of watching videos. Its an incredible piece of tech, where almost everyone from a baby watching animation videos, to an elderly watching an old classic song video has something for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, every night I open Facebook and then check anything new interesting is posted. It takes about 5-10 minutes, then I move to Youtube and before you know it 1 hour has passed. Ever since Trump came into the picture I and the whole world has become obsess into any news related to him. You just cannot take your eyes off him. To understand him and analysis him, I found a talk show called ‘Morning Joe’ very interesting. The hosts does a balance job of showing both sides view, also they have good guests. Apart from those videos, I watch late night shows snippets which are always fun. Like “Jimmy Kimmel”, “Jimmy Fallon”, “Conan”, “Ellen” etc. Then I can check music, comedy, tech videos and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see I find myself sucked into it. So during Lent I followed my brother into banning myself from watching Youtube. The month has passed, and I can say apart from few days, it was easier than I thought. Giving up on something can sometimes be a very refreshing experience. It also proves self-control, in this day and age I can probably say if I had to I could live without tech for long period and that is reassuring to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S : I have gone back to the old habit of watching Youtube, now i follow a partial ban of Tuesday and Thursday, let see if that works out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I won’t hit somebody else’s child</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/04/01/why-i-wont-hit-somebody-elses-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2017/04/01/why-i-wont-hit-somebody-elses-child/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the story, some years ago while I was helping in my dad’s shoe shop I went to a tea shop to buy tea. This tea shop is a very old one, and we have been going there for many many years, so I know them pretty well. Previously the owner was an old man after he passed away his sons took over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that day I went to buy tea, I was waiting while the guy was making it. In comes, a crying child followed by his dad. The dad is the brother of the tea maker. An argument started between them, apparently, the tea maker who is the uncle of the crying child had hit the boy. It was because the boy had misbehaved and after the uncle had tried to correct him, the child had used foul language. This pissed off the uncle and he then hit the boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crying boy went to his dad to complain, and so his dad came to confront his brother in the tea shop. The tea maker argued that he had the right to correct the boy as he was misbehaving. The father and here is the main point of the story, went on to say, ‘When you become a father, then you go and correct your own child, stay away from mine,’ He went away after that, but the words affected the tea maker so much that he had tears in his eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s quite another feeling you get when you see a grown-up cry. I can sort of understand how he felt. So i decided not to hit someone else child, even if the kid is really misbehaving. I remind myself if my brother told me what the father said to his brother, that would totally kill me inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple life rule, if you are not a parent, don’t try to be one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When will you get married?</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2014/12/01/when-will-you-get-married/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2014/12/01/when-will-you-get-married/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this, you probably have asked me this question already or you have thought about it. If by chance you have landed on this site and do not know me, for your sake I am giving a little background. I am a 33 years old man and still single( as of the year 2015). So anyone who basically cares about me is a little bit worried about my current status :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an attempt to answer this question. My current state about marriage is what I call &amp;ldquo;Thunderbolt&amp;rdquo; state. OK, need to explain how I arrived at this. This term is basically picked up from one of my favorite book &amp;ldquo;Godfather&amp;rdquo; by Mario Puzo. (If you have not read it, I recommend it). So this is what happens in the book, Michael Corleone after killing a police officer runs away to Sicily and lives in exile. There he meets a woman who he is instantly attracted to. His bodyguards claim that Michael has been hit by what Sicilians calls &amp;ldquo;the Thunderbolt&amp;rdquo;. Michael soon marries the woman. If you start to think &amp;ldquo;Godfather&amp;rdquo; is a romantic novel, here is the bummer. The woman shortly gets blown by a bomb!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is my point about marriage, unless a &amp;ldquo;Thunderbolt&amp;rdquo; hits me, I am staying happily single. The only issue now for me is, how do you explain to your parents that you have been inspired by a cold-blooded killer, they will kill you!! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goechala</title>
      <link>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2013/07/01/goechala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hsushenon@gmail.com (Hsu Shen On)</author>
      <guid>https://richardhsu.net/ray2/2013/07/01/goechala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks back I went to trekking with some friends to a place call Goechala(Sikkim). Here are few comments and photos about that experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trek is a long, adventurous journey undertaken on foot in areas where common means of transport are generally not available.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walking&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s one of the strange things in life I like to do, it is a habit I picked up from my childhood. In those days I walked to places(rather than take public transport) to save few rupees :) , but now I still do it just because I like it. I guess I like it because I enjoy that pace of traveling and like looking at things. It also facilitates the thinking process(there are few problems in life I fixed while walking :) ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons I went for trekking. In total, we walked almost 90 kms in about 7 days that&amp;rsquo;s more than 10 kms per day!! One day we started at 2 am at night and finished at 1 pm in the afternoon, that&amp;rsquo;s almost 12 hours of walking!! We were like walking on a road which did not end. Trekking is a real test of both physical and mental strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snow&lt;/strong&gt; My one wish was to see snow, I have never seen it in real life except inside a fridge. It was a wonderful site, snow everywhere, once it was snowing when we were walking. The flip side is, it is terribly difficult to walk on snow/ice. More than once I fell down. One of the very important things is to get a very good shoe with grip for trekking. I had bought an expensive “Spalding” shoe for this, after a while(and few falls) I realize, that was not working for me and switched to cheaper “Titas” shoe(from my dad shop cost 5 times lesser!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toilet&lt;/strong&gt; Ok, dont read this part if you do not like toilet humor :). One of the reasons I think that ladies might stay away from trekking is this. If you are a very hygienic person you will have lots of problems. The toilets(when available) are what I call “medieval type” there is a small enclosure and inside a hole. There are many times you will rather not use this toilet and do it in nature&amp;rsquo;s one cause some people’s aim is not quite right  (There were many ladies going on the trek and one was in our group. I was very impressed by the determination shown by her. It&amp;rsquo;s just that you need to get the right mental setup.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mountain&lt;/strong&gt; You will not believe the view, it&amp;rsquo;s simply breathtaking, it makes all the hard work worthwhile. You see the photos and say wow but if you see it in real it&amp;rsquo;s something else, you can&amp;rsquo;t really describe it. I was a bit down one day but one look at the mountain and my spirit went up instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos: &lt;a href=&#34;https://500px.com/hsushenon/galleries/goechala&#34;&gt;https://500px.com/hsushenon/galleries/goechala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
